Finding Aid for the Abiko Family Papers, ca. 1890-1944 LSC.1690
UCLA Library Special Collections
Abiko family papers
circa 1890-1944
UCLA Library Special Collections
Abiko family
LSC.1690
2 oversize_boxes
Kyutaro Abiko (1865-1936) was the longtime publisher of the Nichibei Shimbun of San Francisco, the leading Japanese daily newspaper published from 1899-1942. He also organized the Central California Land Company. In 1909, he married Yonako Abiko (1880-1944). After the death of Kyutaro in 1936, Yonako Abiko became publisher of the Nichibei Shimbun. During World War II, she was briefly interned at the Tanforan Assembly Center in San Bruno, California. The couple had a son, Yasuo Abiko (1910-88). The collection consists of correspondence, diaries, photographs, and memorabilia related to the Abiko family. Most of the material in the collection is in Japanese, but some is in English as well.
44 boxes (22 linear ft.)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Lily Abiko, 1992.
General note
[characters] indicates Japanese characters included in the print version of this online finding aid, available for consultation at the UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 994621253606533
General note
[characters] indicates Japanese characters included in the print version of this online finding aid, available for consultation at the UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections.
Biography
Kyutaro Abiko (1865-1936) was an Issei pioneer who came to the U.S. in 1885; he was the longtime publisher of the Nichibei Shimbun of San Francisco, the leading Japanese daily newspaper published from 1899-1942; he also organized the Central California Land Company; he married Yonako Abiko (1880-1944), in 1909, the same year she came to the U.S.; she graduated from a private Methodist mission school and Tsuda College, a women's school in Japan which was established by her older sister, Tsuda Umeko; after the death of her husband in 1936, Yonako Abiko became publisher of the Nichibei Shimbun; during World War II, she was briefly interned at the Tanforan Assembly Center in San Bruno, California, and she later died in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, in 1944; the couple had a son, Yasuo Abiko (1910-88).
Biographical Narrative
The Abiko family was a very prominent Japanese immigrant family of San Francisco, California. A native of Niigata Prefecture, Abiko Kyutaro [characters] (1865-1936) was an Issei pioneer who immigrated to the United States in 1885. He was born as Kobayashi Kyutaro [characters], but assumed the family name of his maternal grandfather, Abiko Taido [characters], by whom he was raised. A devout Christian throughout his life, Abiko was first exposed to Christianity through an English missionary who was active in his home Prefecture. In 1882 he moved to Tokyo where he was baptized in 1883. As a young student in the capitol, he studied English, French, and the Chinese classics at several private academies. After arriving in the United States, he continued his education in San Francisco where he attended Lincoln Grammar School and graduated from Boys High School in 1891. In 1892 he matriculated into the University of California.
Abiko was a successful businessman, newspaper publisher, and highly respected Japanese community leader. He was the president of the Nichibei Kangyosha [characters] [Japanese American Industrial Corporation], a labor contracting company which supplied Japanese immigrant labor to the Utah Sugar Company, Union Pacific Coal Company, and various railway companies in the western United States. He was the longtime publisher of the Nichibei Shimbun [characters] [Japanese American News] of San Francisco, the most influential Japanese immigrant daily published from 1899 to 1942. And he was the founder and head of the Beikoku Shokusan Kaisha [characters] [The American Land and Produce Company], an agricultural landholding company established for the benefit of Japanese immigrant farmers.
As a community leader, Abiko was at the forefront in the Japanese immigrants' struggle against the anti-Japanese exclusion movement. On the one hand, he labored tirelessly to educate Americans about Japan and Japanese immigrants in the belief that American ignorance was at the bottom of the anti-Japanese exclusion movement. On the other hand, he encouraged Japanese immigrants to sink roots in American soil and to adapt themselves to American society. Like many European immigrants, Japanese immigrants came to the United States with the initial intent of returning to their homeland. In order to persuade Japanese immigrants to cast off their sojourning ideal, Abiko realized that they had to develop an economic and social stake in American society. In the belief that they were suited ideally to take up farming, he exhorted them to settle on land and become agricultural producers. Indeed, Abiko was instrumental in establishing the Yamato and Cortez colonies, two Japanese immigrant agricultural settlements in Central California. And in keeping with his advocacy of permanent settlement, he also encouraged Japanese immigrant males to summon wives from Japan.
Mrs. Abiko Yonako [characters] (1880-1944) was a native of Tokyo. She was the seventh child and fifth daughter of Tsuda Sen & Hatsu [characters]. At the age of ten, she was adopted by her paternal aunt, Suto Yae [characters] and her husband, Suto Yonekichi [characters]. Mrs. Abiko married Abiko Kyutaro in 1909 and came to the United States in that year. One of her older sisters was Tsuda Umeko [characters] who was one of five Japanese girls sent by the Meiji government in 1871 to study in the United States. After eleven years in America, Tsuda Umeko returned to Japan and eventually established Tsuda College [characters] (initially called Joshi Eigaku Juku [characters]) in 1900, a women's school renown for its education in the English language and English literature. Mrs. Abiko, as a graduate of a private Methodist mission school, the Peeresses' School [characters], and Tsuda College itself, was a highly educated Issei woman who had a fluent command of English. Along with her husband, she was very active both within and without the Japanese immigrant community, and after the death of her husband in 1936, she became the publisher of the Nichibei Shimbun. During the wartime years, she was briefly interned at the Tanforan Assembly Center and died in Philadelphia in 1944. The couple had a son, Yasuo [characters] (1910-1988).
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, diaries, photographs, and memorabilia related to the Abiko family. The majority of the collection is made up of Yonako Abiko's personal papers, including her 51 diaries (1891-1944) and approximately 1,000 pieces of incoming correspondence (1896-1944). Most of the correspondence is letters from members of her immediate family. The collection also contains scrapbooks, photo albums, and other materials related to the 1925 and 1926 Nichibei Shimbun-sponsored Nisei kengakudan and the operations of the Nichibei Shimbun during the 1930s. Also includes correspondence and memorabilia related to Yonako Abiko's husband, Kyutaro Abiko, and son, Yasuo Abiko. Most of the material in the collection is in Japanese, but some is in English as well.
Expanded Scope and Content
The Abiko Family Papers consist primarily of Mrs. Abiko's personal papers. These include her diaries, incoming correspondence files, personal memorabilia, photographic albums, and other family-related papers. Her diaries, consisting of 51 items, span the years from 1891 to 1944. The incoming correspondence files include approximately 1,000 letters covering the period 1896 to 1944. Most of the letters are from members of her immediate family, among whom are:
Tsuda Sen [characters], father
Tsuda Hatsu [characters], mother
Suto Yae [characters], paternal aunt and adopted mother
Suto Yonekichi [characters], uncle and adopted father
Uyeno Kotoko [characters], oldest sister
Uyeno Eizaburo [characters], brother-in-law and husband of Kotoko
Tsuda Umeko [characters], older sister
Tsuda Motochika [characters], older brother
Tsuda Jiro [characters], older brother
Tsuda Fukiko [characters], older sister
Wada Jun [characters], older brother
Wada Hanako [characters], sister-in-law and wife of Jun
Tsuda (Shishiuchi) Mariko [characters], older sister
Sakabe Tomiko [characters], younger sister
Sakabe Jiro [characters], brother-in-law and husband of Tomiko
Oi Emiko [characters], niece and eldest daughter of Kotoko
Oi Fukuko [characters], niece and second daughter of Kotoko
Oi Hiromitsu [characters], husband of Emiko
The correspondence files also include many other Japanese letters from her husband, friends, and associates as well as English letters from white Americans and Nisei. Among her white American correspondents are Mary R.E. Nitobe, wife of Nitobe Inazo [characters]; Joseph Elkinton, friend and brother of Mary R.E. Nitobe; Sara W. Elkinton, wife of Joseph Elkinton; Anna C. Hartshorne, friend and benefactor of Tsuda College, and others connected to the school.
In addition, the Abiko Family Papers include scrapbooks, photo albums, and other materials relating to the 1925 and 1926 Nichibei Shimbun-sponsored Nisei kengakudan [characters]; the Tsuda College Emergency Committee established in the aftermath of the Great Kanto Earthquake in order to raise funds to rebuild Tsuda College; Abiko Kyutaro's personal memorabilia, including fragments of his incoming correspondence and materials pertaining to his death and funeral in 1936; materials relating to the operation of the Nichibei Shimbun during the 1930s, including the 1931 strike; Yasuo Abiko's personal memorabilia; and Yasuo Abiko's postwar Nichi Bei Jiji [characters] [Nichi Bei Times] files. (Researchers should note that there are additional sources relating to Abiko Kyutaro in the Oka Shigeki [characters] Papers.)
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Abiko Yonako diaries, 1891-1944 (Boxes 1-5).
Abiko Yonako personal memorabilia (Boxes 6-12).
Incoming correspondence in Japanese (Boxes 13-25).
Incoming correspondence in English (Boxes 26-29).
Nichibei Shimbun Kengakudan, 1925-26 (Boxes 30-32).
Tsuda College Emergency Committee (Box 33).
Abiko Kyutaro personal memorabilia (Boxes 34-35).
Nichibei Shimbun documents (Boxes 36-38).
Yasuo Abiko personal memorabilia (Box 39).
Yasuo Abiko Nichi Bei Jiji files (Boxes 40-41).
Photographs (Boxes 42-44).
Oversize items.
Related Material
Japanese American Research Project Collection (Collection 2010). Available at the Department of Special Collections, UCLA.
Diaries.; Japanese American families -- California -- San Francisco -- Archives.; Publishers and publishing -- California -- San Francisco -- Archives.; Abiko, Kyutaro; Abiko, Yasuo; Abiko, Yonako--Archives.; Abiko, Yonako
- Abiko Yonako Diaries, 1891-1944.; 51 items.
  - July 15, 1891; November 24-December 19, 1892; April 4-May 10, 1894; February 28, 1895-October 18, 1896; January-November 1897. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1898-1900. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1901-1903. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1904-1905. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - (January 1-22, 1907 in English)., 1906-1907 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - February 9, 1906-1909. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1910-January 1-3, February 12, 1911. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - , plus March 31, June 5-9, 1912. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1913-1914. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - January 1-December 10, 1915-1916. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1917-1918. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - (1921 partially in English)., 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - (partially in English)., January 1, February 9-December 20, 1922-January 1-7, January 31-October 31, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - (in Japanese and English)., January 1-5, March 17-19, July 13-16, August 22-27, October 25-November 26, 1925; February 20, 23-June 2, July 12-October 1927 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - (1931 in Japanese and English)., 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1932-1933. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1939. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1940. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1941. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1942-February 12, 1944. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Abiko Yonako Personal Memorabilia
  - 2 Address Books. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 2 Address Books. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Address Book. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 3 Appointment Diaries, 1926, 1930, 1940. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 4 Alumni Association Membership Books, 1910, 1931, 1940, 1941. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Identification and Membership Cards, 11 items, 1937-1942. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Calling Cards. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Bank Deposit Book, August 1918-April 1919. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Daily Record of Family Food Expenses, May-October 1927. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Expense Account book, November 1897-January 1898., 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Abiko Family Account book, 1918; 1936-1939. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Abiko Family Account book, November 1922-July 1929. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Abiko Family Account book, July 1929-July 1933. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Abiko Family Account book, May 1942-February 1944. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 2 Notebooks. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Drawing Exercises. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Birth Records. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Marriage Records, 1909. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 2 Recipe Books. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 9 Flower Arrangement Textbooks, 1895-1896. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 4 English Speech Texts. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 2 Autograph Books, 1907-1908. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Autograph Book, 1915-1936. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Autograph Book, 1939-1941. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Take no Hitofushi, [characters], A collection of poems by an anonymous poetess. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 6 School Notebooks, 1888-1895. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - English Composition Exercise Sheets. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 2 English Composition Exercise Books. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Calligraphic Exercises. (Box 9, Folder 4-6)
  - 22 School Grade Transcripts, 1891-1898. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 5 School Certificates and Diplomas, 1891-1896. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Peeresses' School Diploma, 1899. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 10 Miscellaneous School Items. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 3 Vocabulary Books., 2 English and 1 French. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - International Conference of Women Workers to Promote Permanent Peace, 1915.; 8 pamphlets. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs, 4 pamphlets; Women's Peace Party, 4 pamphlets; Washington Club., 5 pamphlets. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Pamphlets., 11 items. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Copy of Ministry of Education Authorization to Tsuda Umeko to Study Abroad, 1871. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Published Materials Related to Tsuda College. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Soko Nihonjin Kirisutokyo Joshi Seinenkai [characters], Kaiko Nijunen [characters] [A Twenty-Year Remembrance], San Francisco, 1932. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Materials Pertaining to Kato Hana, 5 items, 1919. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Materials. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Hand written Note, Tsuda Family Tree. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Materials Pertaining to Suto Yae., 5 items. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Incoming Correspondence to Parents and Siblings, 9 items, 1881-1908. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Funerals: Tsuda Motochika,, 2 Programs & Inheritance report; Tsuda Hatsu,, Program & Death Notice Telegram; Suto Yae,, Program, 2 Obituaries, & Farewell Poems by Tsuda Mariko., 1908 1909 1925 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Family Telegrams After the Great Kanto Earthquake, 1923. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - University of Colorado Navy Japanese Language School, 5 items, 2 Job applications, resume, & 2 letters., 1943 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - 3 Letters to Parents: 2 to Suto Yonekichi, (), [] & 1 to Tsuda parents, []., March 20, 1890 February 11, 1898 January 7, 1892 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - 3 Letters to Husband, (), (), & ()., March 10, [1913] March 12, [1913] December 8, [1925] (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - 4 Letters to Kitazawa Buemon [characters], (]), (), (), & ()., September 11, [1942 January 5, 1942 January 3, 1944 January 19, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Farewell Poems, 11 envelopes, February 24, 1944. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Materials on Memorial Services, 1944. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - 6 Letters of Condolence, 1944. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Materials. (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Incoming Family Correspondence to Abiko Yonako
  - Suto Yae, 1896-1923; 293 Letters & 5 Postcards
    - 8 Letters. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - [July 20, 1896]. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - [July 27, 1896]. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - (September 5, [1896]). (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - (September 20, [1896]),., 2 Letters. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - (September 21, [1896])., 2 Letters. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - (December 10, [1896]). (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 9 Letters. (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - [January 13, 1897]. (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - [February 10, 1897]. (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - (February 19, [1897])., 2 Letters. (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - [March 25, 1897]. (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - (April 11, [1897]). (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - (April 11, 1897). (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - (June 24, [1897]). (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - (July 3, [1897]). (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - 10 Letters. (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - (February 7, [1898]),., Postscript. (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - (March 16, [1898]),., Enclosure, Programs for Musicale, March 15, 1898. (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - (April 15, [1898]). (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - (May 19, [1898]). (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - (June 17, [1898]). (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - (July 27, [1898]). (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - (September 7, [1898]). (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - (October 19, [1898]). (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - ([October] 26, [1898]). (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - (December 4, [1898]). (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - 6 Letters. (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - [January 21, 1899],., Fragment. (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - (February 23, [1899]). (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - (March 22, [1899]). (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - (March 27, [1899]),., Postscript. (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - (March 31, [1899]),., Enclosure, Building sketch. (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - (April 6, [1899]). (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - 6 Letters. (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - (April 18, [1899]). (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - (May 17, [1899]). (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - (May 21, [1899]). (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - (June 29, [1899]). (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - (July 9, [1899]). (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - (August 23, [1899]). (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - 8 Undatable Letters, ca. 1896-1908. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - 8 Undatable Letters, ca. 1896-1908. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Letters., 13 Letters & 1 Postcard. (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - (April 30, [1906]). (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - (June 7, [1906]). (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - (February 7, [1907]),., Postscript. (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - (March 14, [1907]). (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - (August 3, [1907]),., 2 Enclosures, 2 letters from Yae, (August 5, [1907]), (August 6, [1907]). (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - (August 23, [1907]). (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - [August 25, 1907],., Postcard. (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - (September 16, [1907]). (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - (October 30, 1907]),., Postscript. (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - (November 7, [1907]),., Enclosure, Letter from Yae, (November 16, [1907]). (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - (December 6, [1907]). (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 9 Letters. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - [August 5, 1908]. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - (February 25, [1909]). (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - [March 8], 1909?. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - (March 10, [1909]). (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - (July 19, [1909])., Postscript. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - (August 25, [1909]). (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - (October 4, [1909]). (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - [December 21, 1909]. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - [December 27, 1909]. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - 7 Letters. (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - (January 1, 1910)., Fragment. (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - [January 9, 1910]. (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - (February 1, [1910]). (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - (March 6, [1910]. (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - (April 12, [1910]). (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - [May 3, 1910]. (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - (June 6, [1910]). (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 9 Letters. (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - [June 14, 1910]. (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - (July 19, 1910)., 3 Letters. (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - [August 15, 1910]. (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - (October 4, 1910). (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - (October 10, [1910])., Postscript. (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - (November 15, [1910])., 2 Letters. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - 2 Undatable Letters, ca. 1908-1910. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - 5 Letters. (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - (April 3, [1911]). (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - (June 11, [1911]). (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - (June 16, [1911]). (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - (July 4, [1911]). (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - (July 25, [1911]). (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 12 Letters. (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - (August 8, [1911]). (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - (August 21, [1911])., Enclosure, photograph. (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - (September 3, [1911])., Enclosures, 2 letters from Yae, (September 5, [1911]), (September 13, [1911]). (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - (October 2, [1911]). (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - (October 10, [1911]). (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - (October 30, [1911]., Enclosure, Postcard. (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - (November 16, [1911]). (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - (November 21, [1911]). (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - [November 24, 1911]. (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - (December 25, [1911])., 2 Postscripts & Enclosures, New Year's Card & letter from Aya, (December 26, [1911]). (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - 8 Letters. (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - [January 4, 1912]. (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - (January 7, [1912])., Enclosure, letter from Yae (January 9, [1912]). (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - (January 15, [1912])., 2 Postscripts. (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - (February 12, [1912]). (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - (April 4, [1912]). (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - (April 12, [1912])., Enclosure, Alma Mater. (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - (May 21, [1912?]). (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - 9 Letters. (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - (June 7, [1912]). (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - (June 21, [1912]). (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - (June 28, [1912?])., 2 Letters. (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - (July 4, [1912]). (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - (July 27, [1912])., 2 Letters. (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - (August 2, [1912]). (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - (August 20, [1912?]). (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Letters., 7 Letters & 1 Postcard. (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - (August 29, [1912?]). (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - (September 6, [1912]). (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - (September 13, [1912]). (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - (October 4, [1912?]). (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - (November 14, [1912?]). (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - (November 29, [1912]). (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - (December 30, 1912). (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - [1912]., Postcard. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Letters., 8 Letters & 1 Postcard. (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - (January 8, [1913])., Fragment. (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - (January 17, [1913]). (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - (February 7, [1913]). (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - (February 21, [1913]). (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - (September 29, [1913])., Postscript. (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - (October 4, [1913])., Postcard. (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - (October 14, [1913]). (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - (October 24, [1913]). (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - (October 31, [1913]). (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - 7 Letters. (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - (February 23, [1914]). (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - (March 17, [1914]). (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - (March 28, [1914]). (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - [April 9, 1914]., Postscript. (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - (April 30, [1914]). (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - (May 4, [1914]). (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - (May 19, [1914]. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - 8 Letters. (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - (July 7, [1914]). (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - (July 20, [1914]). (Box 16, Folder 3)